export const chapter = "Chapter - 12: The Machine Age  ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What is the term used to describe the period before the discovery of metals when early humans used tools made of bones, stones, and wood?",
        optionA: "Copper Age",
        optionB: "Iron Age",
        optionC: "Stone Age",
        correctAnswer: "C) Stone Age",
      },
      {
        question: "What was the first metal used by early humans?",
        optionA: "Iron",
        optionB: "Copper",
        optionC: "Bronze",
        correctAnswer: "B) Copper",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The age following the Stone Age, characterized by the use of copper and tin to make tools, is known as the:",
        optionA: "Bronze Age",
        optionB: "Iron Age",
        optionC: "Industrial Age",
        correctAnswer: "A) Bronze Age",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which inventor is credited with the invention of the steam engine in 1769?",
        optionA: "Thomas Edison",
        optionB: "Alexander Graham Bell",
        optionC: "James Watt",
        correctAnswer: "C) James Watt",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Industrial Revolution marked the transition from hand-made goods to:",
        optionA: "Animal-powered goods",
        optionB: "Machine-made goods",
        optionC: "Water-powered goods",
        correctAnswer: "B) Machine-made goods",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the primary source of energy for machines in the early stages of the Industrial Revolution?",
        optionA: "Electricity",
        optionB: "Coal",
        optionC: "Petroleum",
        correctAnswer: "B) Coal",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which by-product of petroleum is widely used as a source of energy in vehicles?",
        optionA: "Kerosene",
        optionB: "Diesel",
        optionC: "Gasoline (Petrol)",
        correctAnswer: "C) Gasoline (Petrol)",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the primary source of electricity generation mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "Burning oil",
        optionB: "Burning coal",
        optionC: "Hydroelectricity",
        correctAnswer: "C) Hydroelectricity",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who conducted the famous kite experiment related to electricity, distinguishing between negative and positive charges?",
        optionA: "Thomas Edison",
        optionB: "Alessandro Volta",
        optionC: "Benjamin Franklin",
        correctAnswer: "C) Benjamin Franklin",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which of the following sources of energy mentioned in the text is considered renewable and eco-friendly?",
        optionA: "Coal",
        optionB: "Solar energy",
        optionC: "Natural gas (CNG)",
        correctAnswer: "B) Solar energy",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The period before the discovery of metals, when early humans used tools made of bones, stones, and wood, is known as the _______________.",
        options: ["Bronze Age", "Iron Age", "Stone Age"],
        correctAnswer: "Stone Age",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The first metal used by early humans is believed to be _______________.",
        options: ["Copper", "Iron", "Bronze"],
        correctAnswer: "Copper",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The age following the Stone Age, characterized by the use of copper and tin to make tools, is known as the _______________.",
        options: ["Bronze Age", "Iron Age", "Industrial Age"],
        correctAnswer: "Bronze Age",
      },
      {
        question:
          "James Watt is credited with the invention of the _______________ in 1769.",
        options: ["Steam engine", "Electric generator", "Gasoline engine"],
        correctAnswer: "Steam engine",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Industrial Revolution marked the transition from hand-made goods to _______________.",
        options: [
          "Animal-powered goods",
          "Machine-made goods",
          "Water-powered goods",
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Machine-made goods",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The primary source of energy for machines in the early stages of the Industrial Revolution was _______________.",
        options: ["Electricity", "Coal", "Petroleum"],
        correctAnswer: "Coal",
      },
      {
        question:
          "_______________ is widely used as a source of energy in vehicles, and it is a by-product of petroleum.",
        options: ["Kerosene", "Diesel", "Gasoline (Petrol)"],
        correctAnswer: "Gasoline (Petrol)",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The primary source of electricity generation mentioned in the text is _______________.",
        options: ["Burning oil", "Burning coal", "Hydroelectricity"],
        correctAnswer: "Hydroelectricity",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Benjamin Franklin conducted a famous kite experiment related to electricity, distinguishing between _______________ charges of electricity.",
        options: [
          "Negative and positive",
          "Electric and magnetic",
          "Light and dark",
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Negative and positive",
      },
      {
        question:
          "_______________ is considered a renewable and eco-friendly source of energy used to run vehicles, cookers, and water heaters.",
        options: ["Coal", "Solar energy", "Natural gas (CNG)"],
        correctAnswer: "Solar energy",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The period before the discovery of metals, when early humans used tools made of bones, stones, and wood, is known as the Bronze Age.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "James Watt is credited with the invention of the steam engine in 1769.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The age following the Stone Age, characterized by the use of copper and tin to make tools, is known as the Iron Age.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Coal was the primary source of energy for machines in the early stages of the Industrial Revolution.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Benjamin Franklin conducted a famous kite experiment related to electricity, distinguishing between negative and positive charges of electricity.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Solar energy is considered a non-renewable source of energy.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The primary source of electricity generation mentioned in the text is burning oil.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The first metal used by early humans is believed to be iron.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Industrial Revolution marked the transition from hand-made goods to water-powered goods.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The government has initiated the Swachh Bharat Mission to promote cleanliness and hygiene and has also taken steps to build schools in all villages.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
